nutritionexp.com 2018-12-14

# Privacy Policy – Nutrition Explained

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit nutritionexp.com (the “Site”).

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you visit the Site, we may automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we may collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

– “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  
– “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.  
– “Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.  
– IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as “traffic data” so that data (such as the Web pages you request) can be sent to you.

#### HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We use the Device Information that we collect to improve and optimize our Site and marketing and advertising campaigns (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

For purposes of hosting and maintenance, your personal data may be archived on servers of the hosting company which hosts our Site.

#### SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above. For example, we use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site–you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

#### BEHAVIOURAL ADVERTISING

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by:  
FACEBOOK – <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads>  
GOOGLE – <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous>  
BING – <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads>

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at: [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

#### DO NOT TRACK

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

#### YOUR RIGHTS

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information might be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

If you wish to raise a complaint regarding how we have processed your personal data, you can contact us with the Contact Us information below, and we will investigate the matter. If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law, you may complain to the data protection officer in the country in which you reside.

#### DATA RETENTION AND HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR DATA

We will not retain your personal data for longer than required. This means that we will keep your personal information: (i) for as long as required by law, (ii) until we no longer have a valid reason for keeping it, or (iii) until you request us to stop using it. When we delete your personal data from our databases, it will remain in our backup system until it cycles out.

#### OUR ADVERTISING PARTNERS

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include

Google  
Amazon  
Taboola  
Outbrain  
Revcontent  
Content.ad  
Clickbank  
Media.net  
Yahoo! Publisher Network  
… and others

Each of these advertising partners has their own Privacy Policy for their site.  
You may consult them to find the privacy policy for each of the advertising partners.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology in their respective advertisements and links that appear on Site and which are sent directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by our site’s third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on the site.

Site has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

#### Third Party Privacy Policies

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Our Site’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

#### MINORS

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

Site does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that hhdresearch.org has in its database the personally-identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact us immediately (using the contact in the first paragraph) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

#### CHANGES

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

#### CONSENT

By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.

#### CONTACT US

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e-mail at [contact@nutritionexp.com](mailto:contact@nutritionexp.com).
